Kathleen Tiley

717.422.7636 | kpt12@georgetown.edu | Portfolio: kptil.github.io/ 3534 Wilson Avenue ● Alexandria VA, 22305

EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science

University of Florida
May 2023 | Gainesville, FL

GPA: 3.97 / 4.00 Coursework:

Data Structures and Algorithms
Database Management Systems
Software Engineering
Penetration Testing
AI/ML Independent Study

MS in Security Studies

Georgetown University
May 2018 | Washington, D.C.
GPA: 3.86 / 4.00

SKILLS

Programming

Proficient: Java | C++ | SQL Learning: JavaScript | Python | Matlab | Lua | R

Tools

Git | MERN Stack | Oracle DB

Methodologies

Object-Oriented Programming | Agile/Scrum

Languages

French (Proficient)
Arabic (Beginner)

PROJECTS

Homeless Helper

Designed MERN web app providing information about local resources for the homeless. Team employed Agile/Scrum process.

SUMMARY

I am a computer science student with a professional background in national intelligence and transferable skills in project management and communication. My experience and academic success demonstrate my ability to solve complex computer science problems and learn challenging concepts. This year, I have learned advanced programming concepts, built web applications using the MERN Stack, and gained experience working on scrum teams following Agile development processes. During the coming semester, I will learn fundamental Machine Learning concepts and gain further experience with MERN Stack web development through my senior capstone project.

EXPERIENCE

L3Harris Technologies, Inc. | Software Engineer Intern, Space and Airborne Systems

May 2022 - September 2022, January 2023 - PRESENT | Herndon, Virginia

- Designed system to orthorectify classified NITF satellite imagery and import images into Command: Modern Operations (CMO) using Lua and Python to satisfy customer request. Senior team members briefed the system to the customer during a program update.
- Independently learned new programming languages, APIs, and mathematical concepts and immediately implemented knowledge to deliver value to the customer.
- Briefed system to program team members and thoroughly documented system processes and tools on Confluence to ensure it remained accessible and useful to the CMO team.
- Networked within program to access existing in-development orthorectification tools to achieve system design goals and improve efficiency.
- Supported MSA Tools Team efforts to refactor existing orthorectification tools.
 Participated in Agile development and scrum processes.

U.S. Consulate General Amsterdam | Community Liaison Office (CLO) Coordinator May 2019 – March 2020 | Amsterdam, The Netherlands

- Collaborated with CLO team to manage an annual program of 35 events.
- Designed a personnel management system for 500+ Mission members to ensure accountability during crises; reduced time spent on CLO reporting by 92% while increasing accuracy by 10%.
- Produced an interactive map in Microsoft Power BI allowing users to quickly visualize U.S. Mission engagement throughout the Netherlands and prioritize engagement targets.

Compiler Model

Implemented the compiler model for a simple language in Java. Designed a Lexer, Parser, Interpreter, Analyzer, and Generator using advanced Java programming techniques.

Active DoD TS/SCI clearance

Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA) | Desk Officer, Defense Attaché Service (DAS) June 2016 – January 2019 | Washington, D.C.

- Managed the daily operations of the US Defense Attaché Office (USDAO) in Ankara, Turkey in a fast-paced, high impact environment.
- Briefed 2-star J2, senior DAS leaders, and incoming attachés on DAO operations and impact.
- Designed data-driven processes in Excel to assess DAO operations and ensure alignment of DAO resources with mission priorities.
- Identified and corrected errors in HQ datasets using Excel to allow DIA to accurately measure the performance of 86 officers across Europe.